＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
That seat is reserved for me...
(ウタカタ)そこは オレの指定席だ。
(ホタル)ウタカタ様！
Utakata-sama!
(ウタカタ)遁兵衛が呼んでるぞ。
Tonbei is looking for you.
(遁兵衛)頼んだぞ。
I'm counting on you.
(アカボシ)またか！
Not again.
They sure went through
a lot of trouble
(チュウシン)こんな だだっ広い平原に
いくつも罠を仕掛けるたぁな…。
setting up this many traps on
such an open field.
ご苦労なこった。
何者かが罠を突破し
砦に迫っております。
Someone is breaking through our traps
and approaching our fort.
Just in case, in accordance with
the late master's instructions,
念のため 先代の教えに従い
木ノ葉隠れの里に➡
I have alerted the Hidden Leaf.
緊急の知らせを放ちました。
並大抵の者では この砦に
近づくこともできませぬが➡
It's impossible for any ordinary person
to get close to our fort.
もし ここまで
敵が押し寄せてきたときは…。
However, if the enemy does succeed
in getting here...
The three of us, including Utakata-sama,
just have to fight together!
ウタカタ様と３人
力を合わせて戦えば大丈夫。
We'll turn the tables on them!
返り討ちです！
Why are they targeting us?
What is their purpose?
なぜ ここが狙われる？
ヤツらの目的は いったい何だ？
おそらく… 我ら一族に伝わる
禁術かと…。
Most likely...
the Forbidden Jutsu that has been
passed down to our clan.
(チュウシン)トラップをかわし続けて
砦に近づけば深い谷。
All these traps,
then as you near the fort,
there's a deep ravine...
更に その向こうに
結界まで張っちゃって。
On top of which is
a barrier beyond that.
Talk about being overly cautious.
ヘッ どんだけ心配性なヤツらなんだ。
なあ そう思わねえか？ ナンゴウ。
Don't you think so, Nango?
(ナンゴウ)あぁ。
Yeah...
You're just not a man of many words...
are you?
(チュウシン)相変わらず
会話がふくらまないね お前は…。
(ベンテン)ムダ話は
そのへんにしときな。 チュウシン。
Chushin, enough of your rambling.
口が軽いと
オツムの中も軽く見えるぞ。
A loose mouth is indicative of
an empty brain.
口を開けば イメージ悪くなるのは
お前のほうじゃないのかい ベンテン。
I'd say you're the one who looks bad
each time you open your mouth.
Benten...
Going through the extremes to
protect something is proof of its value!
(アカボシ)相手が
必死に守ろうとするのは➡
それだけ価値がある
という証拠だ！
陣形を取れ！
Get into your positions.
That must be it...
《アカボシ : あそこか…》
破!!
What?! The barrier has been broken.
なに！ 結界が破られた。
ヤツら… ただ者ではないな。
These guys... are not ordinary people.
Benten!
ベンテン！
任せろ！
Leave them to me!
Next is mountain climbing.
お次は山登りか。
(遁兵衛)ホタル様 これを…。
Hotaru-sama, take this...
おじい様から伝わりし
禁術を守るため➡
In order to protect the Forbidden Jutsu
that your grandfather passed down,
ひとまず 一族の隠れる山里へ
ウタカタ様とともに お逃げくだされ。
you and Utakata-sama must escape
to our hidden village.
What about you?
遁兵衛は…。
すぐに あとを追いまする。
I will follow immediately.
Now you must hurry...
さあ 早く…。
ダメです！
No! If we're to escape,
the three of us will go together.
逃げるなら３人一緒に。
The enemy is at our doorstep.
敵は すぐそばまで
迫っているのですぞ。
This is not the time for
self-indulgence.
今は そのようなワガママを
言っている場合では。
来ないのか？
You're not coming?
さぁ ホタル様。
Go, Hotaru-sama.
ウタカタ殿。
Utakata-dono!
Please... take care of Hotaru-sama.
ホタル様のこと
くれぐれも お頼み申す。
The debt I owe you will be repaid...
借りは返す。
わ～ おっとっと…。
Phew, that was close.
いや 危な…。
This isn't gonna be
an ordinary climb, Akaboshi.
ただの山登りじゃ
すまないらしいぜ アカボシ。
頂上じゃ
何が待ち受けているのか➡
I can't wait to see what's waiting
for us at the summit.
楽しみになってきたな。
(遁兵衛)ホタル様
道中くれぐれも油断なきよう。
Hotaru-sama...
Please be extremely careful
while traveling.
ウタカタ様のおそばを
決して離れては いけませんぞ。
You must not leave Utakata-sama's side.
遁兵衛 必ず後から来るのですよ。
Tonbei, you must follow us later.
Promise me that!
約束です。
ホタル様は➡
Hotaru-sama, think only of
your own safety. Nothing else!
自身の安全のみを心配なされ！
《役の行者様
一時でも時間を稼ぎ…》
En no Gyoja-sama... I promise to buy
as much time as possible...
So I can protect Hotaru-sama!
《ホタル様を お守りする》
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Wanderer
(シズネ)綱手様 このようなものが。
Tsunade-sama, we received this...
(綱手)なに!?
What?!
(カツユ)あぁ～！
(カカシ)カツユ様。
あぁ カカシさん。
Katsuyu-sama!
Oh, Kakashi...
(キバ)なんだ カツユ様が
わざわざ お出迎えか？
What? Katsuyu-sama came
all the way to greet us?
(シノ)いや 違う。
No, she didn't.
どうやら
厄介ごとが起こったらしい。
There must be trouble.
Because...
なぜなら…。
(ヤマト)綱手様がカツユ様を
お使いになるのは➡
Tsunade-sama only uses
Katsuyu-sama during emergencies.
緊急のときだけだろうから。
なるほど 緊急事態ってことか。
I get it! So there's an urgent situation.
《ヒナタ : シノ君 わかるわ。
I know how you feel, Shino...
言いたいことが
言えなかったときの気持…》
When you aren't allowed to finish
what you wanted to say...
(シズネ)密約… ですか？
A secret treaty?
第三次忍界大戦のとき➡
During the Third Great Ninja War,
a certain jutsu passed down
土蜘蛛一族の頭領
役の行者が伝えるある術が➡
by En no Gyoja, the leader
of the Tsuchigumo Clan,
里一つを丸ごと焼き尽くした。
wiped out an entire village.
(綱手)あまりに危険なその術を➡
The Third Hokage demanded that
such a dangerous jutsu
禁術にするよう要請したのが➡
be classified as a Forbidden Jutsu.
三代目火影 その代償として➡
And in exchange, it was agreed that
the Hidden Leaf would provide aid
土蜘蛛一族が
危機に陥ったときには➡
木ノ葉が守るという
約束を交わした。
to the Tsuchigumo clan
in time of danger.
(カツユ)カカシさんは 報告のため
里に戻るようにとのことです。
Kakashi-san, you are to report to the village
for details from your last mission.
わかりました。
Understood.
事は一刻を争う。
We're battling against time.
第七班は隊長のヤマトと共に➡
Team 7 will go with Captain Yamato
大至急 葛城山へ向かえ。
(サクラ)はい。
and head for
Mount Katsuragi immediately.
Yes, sir!
(ナルト)なぁ なんでカカシ先生が
一緒じゃねんだ？
Why aren't you coming,
Kakashi-sensei?
(サクラ)えっ!?
ボクでは不満だと？
Is there a problem if it's just me?
そういう意味じゃ
ねえってばよ。
That's not what I meant...
すでに 役の行者は
１年前に亡くなり➡
En no Gyoja passed away a year ago
and the fort on Mount Katsuragi
葛城山の砦には➡
孫娘のホタルが 従者１人と
ともに暮らしている。
is occupied by his granddaughter,
Hotaru, and her servant.
砦を襲うヤツらの目的は➡
Whoever is attacking the fort
is undoubtedly
役の行者の
禁術に違いない。
after En no Gyoja's Forbidden Jutsu.
禁術が
他の忍に奪われることは➡
We must prevent the theft of
the Forbidden Jutsu at all cost.
なんとしても
防がねばならない。
ナルト君を向かわせたのは…。
Why did you send Naruto-kun too?
(綱手)対 暁の対策として
泳がせる意味もある。
It's a countermeasure against
the Akatsuki.
電！
光！
石！
火！
(チュウシン)このジジイ １人で砦を
守りきるつもりだったのかねぇ。
Did this old man intend to
protect the fort all by himself?
(アカボシ)しかし 思ったより
手間取った。
Still, this took longer than planned.
急いで捜索開始だ。
Let's hurry and start the search.
あれが 土蜘蛛一族の砦…。
That's the Tsuchigumo clan's fort?!
ヤマト隊長。
Captain Yamato!
Hm?
ここで 何があったんだ？
What happened here?
戦闘ではなさそうだ。
サイ どうだい？
It doesn't look like this is from a fight...
Sai, how about it?
(サイ)砦の方向に
向かっている新しい足跡が。
There are fresh footprints headed
towards the fort...
敵は４人です。
The enemy is a group of four.
これは
砦の周りのトラップだよ。
These are from traps surrounding
the fort.
敵は うまく
かわしたらしいけどね。
It looks like the enemy avoided them.
じゃあ このあたりには
まだ罠が？
Then there are more in this area?
だから このトラップの跡を
たどっていけばいいってことさ。
We'll just follow the trail of trap marks.
そっか それなら
罠にひっかからずに➡
I get it!
That way, we'll get to the fort
without encountering any fresh traps!
砦まで行けるってわけか。
役の行者の禁術は
どこに隠した!!
Where is the Forbidden Jutsu
of En no Gyoja?!
お前は負けたんだ 潔く吐け。
(遁兵衛)知らん。
You lost, so 'fess up.
I know nothing.
(チュウシン)しらばっくれても
ムダだってんだよ！
Playing dumb is useless!
孫娘…。
ん？
The granddaughter.
そういやあ ここには
役の行者の孫娘がいるはずだな。
That's right. En no Gyoja
has a granddaughter.
娘を逃がしたか。
禁術もソイツが？
Did you let her escape?
She has the Forbidden Jutsu?
そうなんだな おい!!
Is that it? Hey!
もういい。
それなら 見当はついてる。
Enough. I know where to find her.
そろそろ 潮時だ。
We're out of time.
It seems we have some interference.
どうやら ジャマ者が現れたようだ。
ヤマト隊長
行き止まりだってばよ。
It's a dead-end, Captain Yamato.
(ヤマト)なら 橋を架ければ
いいだけさ。
We'll just lay a bridge across it.
木遁の術！
Wood Style!
さっすが ヤマト隊長！
ボクが一緒で
よかったでしょ？
Gotta hand it to you, Captain Yamato!
Aren't you glad I was here?
しつこいってばよ！
Don't rub it in.
しっかりしろ じいさん。
Hang on, old man!
弱いけど脈はあるわ。
助かる。
It's weak, but he still has a pulse.
He'll live.
ひと足遅かったか。
We were one step too late...
サイ 他に誰かいないか
周辺を調べてくれ。
Sai, check the area to see
if there are any others.
はい。
Right.
気がついたか？
You've come to...
私たちは 木ノ葉隠れの里より
警護のために派遣された者です。
We are from the Hidden Leaf
and were dispatched to
provide assistance.
あなたは
ホタル様の従者とお見うけするが。
You are Hotaru-sama's servant,
I presume?
私は 遁兵衛です。
I am... Tonbei...
ホ… ホタル様は➡
H-Hotaru-sama is headed for
土蜘蛛一族が隠れ住む
山里に向かいました。
the hidden village of
the Tsuchigumo clan.
屋敷の奥に 入口を崩された
抜け穴らしきものがある。
There is an escape route with
a collapsed entry
そこを通って ホタル様は…。
in the back of the mansion.
Hotaru-sama went... through there...
わかりました。
我々も あとを追います。
I understand. We will follow her.
サクラ！ このまま 遁兵衛殿の治療を
続けてくれ。
Sakura, stay here and tend
to Tonbei-dono's injuries.
はい！
ナルト！ サイ！ すぐに出発だ！
Right.
Naruto, Sai, let's go.
(ホタル)ウタカタ様。
お聞きしたいことが
あるのですが…。
Utakata-sama, there's something
I'd like to ask you...
隠れ里に着いたあとも➡
私に 術を教えてくださいますか？
Will you teach me jutsu even
after we get to the hidden village?
オレは 何も教えたつもりはない。
I don't recall teaching you anything.
でも 砦では➡
いろいろな修業を
つけてくださって…！
But back at the fort,
you trained me in many things.
それは お前が
勝手にやっていたことだ。
You did that on your own...
それに…
里に着けば オレは用なしだ。
Also, when we reach the village,
I will no longer be needed.
ウタカタ様ほど強いお人は
里にはいません！
There's no one stronger than you
in the village!
それに私は ウタカタ様に
お教えいただきたいのです！
And I want you to teach me.
That time, when you saved me...
あの時
私を助けていただいたとき…！
((キャ～ッ!!
しつこいヤツらだ！
Persistent guys...
《なに？ あの術！ すごい！》
What is... that jutsu?
It's amazing!
これで ヤツらに
居場所を知られたな！
Now they know my location...
しばらく 人目を避けて
移動しなければ…。
For the time being,
I must stay out of view as I move.
大丈夫ですか!?
Are you all right?!
その傷…。
よろしければ 私たちの砦で➡
That wound...
Allow me to treat it back at our fort.
治療させてもらえませんか？
助けていただいたお礼といっては
なんですが…。
That's the least I can do
for coming to my aid.
《砦？》
うっ！
Fort?
あっ！
しっかりしてください！
今 助けを呼んできます！
Please hang on!
(それまで
ここで ジッとしていてください！))
I'm going to get help.
Don't move from this spot!
《ウタカタ : クソッ！
チャクラを使いすぎだ…な…》
- Damn! I used too much chakra.
- I'll be right back...
あの時 私も➡
ウタカタ様のように
なりたいと思ったのです！
At that time, I wanted to become
like you, Utakata-sama!
オレは別に
お前を助けたわけじゃない。
I didn't save you that time...
でも…！
襲ってきた忍たちは お前じゃなく
オレを狙っていたのだ。
But...!
The ninja who attacked were coming
after me, not you.
オレは 自分の身を守るために
戦っただけだ。
I just fought in order to protect myself.
そうだとしても➡
私は ウタカタ様を見て
強くなりたいと思ったんです！
Even so, after watching you,
いえ… 強くならなければ
いけないんです！
I knew I wanted to be strong
like you. No, I must.
そのために ウタカタ様の術を…！
That is why I wish to learn your jutsu...
強ければいいのか？
えっ？
Being strong is enough for you?
Huh?
人に つけ狙われるような人間に
教えてもらったことを➡
You may end up regretting being taught
by one who is a wanted man.
あとで 後悔するように
なるかもしれないぞ。
私は ウタカタ様を信じています。
どんなことがあっても
ウタカタ様を 一生 師匠として…。
I trust you, Utakata-sama.
No matter what happens,
I will always consider you my master.
オレを師匠と呼ぶな!!
Don't call me your master!
しまった！
その子から離れろ！
Shoot!
Step away from that girl!
《影分身？
A Shadow Clone?
面倒な…》
What a bother...
おとなしく 捕まりやが…。
ダメ！
その方は 敵ではありません！
Give it up and be captured--!
No!
He is not an enemy!
(ヤマト)ナルト！
Naruto!
早とちりしたようで
すみませんでした。
Pardon him for jumping to conclusions.
遁兵衛殿より ホタル様のことだけは
聞いていたのですが。
Tonbei-dono had told us only
about Hotaru-sama...
遁兵衛は 無事なんですね？
はい。
Tonbei is alive and well?
今 医療班が看護しています。
Yes. He's under the care
of our medic.
よかった。
(ヤマト)ここからは 我々も
護衛に加わります。
I'm glad...
From here on, you have
our protection as well.
ほんとに 悪かったってばよ。
Hey, I'm really sorry.
あとは任せても 大丈夫だな？
I can leave the rest to you then...
ああ。
任務は きっちり やりぬくって…。
Huh?
Sure thing!
I always fulfill my missions...
世話になった。 じゃあな。
Huh?
Thanks... Take care.
ウタカタ様！
Utakata-sama!
おい！ どこ行くんだ？
Hey, where're you going?
せめて 隠れ里まで
一緒に行ってもらえませんか？
Can't you at least stay with me until
we reach the hidden village?
アイツらは 強い。
頼っても大丈夫だ。
Those guys are strong...
You can rely on them.
私には 護衛よりも 術を
教えてくれる人が必要なのです。
I don't need guards!
I need someone to teach me jutsu!
お願いです。 私と一緒に…。
Come with me, please...
修業は
今まで以上に真剣にやります！
I'll be more serious than ever
in my training!
どんなにつらい訓練でも
決して泣きごとは言いません！
I'll endure anything and
I promise never to cry! And...
そして ウタカタ様を
二度と師匠とは…。
And I'll never call you
my master... ever... again...
師匠とは…。
ウタカタ師匠のバカ～!!
Stupid Master Utakata!
それは 禁句だと言っただろ。
I told you not to call me that...
オレは 師匠と呼ばれるほど
バカじゃない。
I'm not foolish enough to
be called master.
here are the answers of the path
koko ni aru no wa kimi ga ima made erande michi no
you chose up till now, look and go on by yourself
kotae tachi yo hora jishin motte susumeba ii
it's very natural, like a rainbow over
totemo shizen na no amaeagari no
asphalt after a rainfall
asufaruto ni niji ga kakaru you ni
a lonely wind blew and
lonely kaze ga fuite
a feeling dawned on me
feeling ki ga tsuita yo
there are any answers anywhere
kotae wo doko ni mo nai kedo
call me, I got it already
call me wakatteru wa
with you, we'll always
with you ai wa itsu mo
love each other
atae au mono
for you
I'm sure one day you will
kitto kimi wa itsu no hi ka
be able to fly in the sky
kono sora wo toberu hazu dakara
no matter how many times we've stumbled for you
nando tsumaizuta to shite mo for you
there's only one thing important
taisetsu na koto wa hitotsu
which is to dream
yumemiru koto
so at least keep your heart open
kokoro dake wa tozasanaide ite
Next Episode
同期のなか ただ１人
いまだ下忍のままの➡
Why are you people following me?
うずまきナルト君。
今日のお客様です！
We're your bodyguards, that's why!
なんか
テンション下がる紹介だなぁ。
There is no need for that.
I can protect myself just fine.
台本に そう書いてあるもんでね。
You Hidden Leaf people may leave.
今日は 台本
忘れなかったんだな。
Don't ask such nonsense!
ああっ！ まだ そのことを言う！
Oh well then. Let's do as she says
and leave.
だって２回もだぜ！
この間は カカシ先輩が
持ってただけだろ！
What?!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Successor of the Forbidden Jutsu"
じゃあ １回目は？
あの日の台本は
トイレに行っている間に➡
Successor of the
Forbidden Jutsu
Now, now, don't worry.
なくなっていて そのあと➡
ラーメンの汁まみれで
発見されたんだ。
ん？ ラーメンの汁？
Among his comrades,
he's the only one who remains a genin.
"Yamato's Room"
((ヘヘヘ… 休憩中に ラーメン ラーメンと。
Our guest today is Uzumaki Naruto-kun.
だっ あっ！ げ～っ！
That was a deflating introduction.
やっべえ！
誰の台本だってばよ？
That's what it says in the script.
あ～ どうしよう？ どうしよう？
So you didn't forget your script today, eh?
こうなりゃ 証拠隠滅！
Are you still gonna bring that up?
ふぅ～ これでよし。
Well, it happened twice!
(本番で～す！
ああ 今 行くってばよ！))
The last time, Kakashi-senpai had it.
あれが ヤマト隊長… の!?
Then how about the first time?
やっぱり… お前か！
That script went missing
while I was using the restroom.
出た～っ!!
Then it was found splattered
with ramen soup.
＜ルーシィ : それは 天にも地にも→
いまだかつて現れたことなき
怪異の顕現＞
Hm? Ramen soup?
Heh heh heh.
Ramen during break time! Ahh!
＜ その異様な姿が
人々の前に立ち現れしとき→
Crap! Whose script is this?
誰もが異様な冷気を
肌身に感じたのであった＞
Oh... what'll I do? What'll I do?
I guess I'll just have to get rid
of the evidence!
もう逃げられんぞ 連続宝石強盗！
All right, done!
We're on air!
Yeah, be right there.
That was... yours, Captain Yamato?!
It was you... I knew it!
Yikes!